KEENEN TOPPLE

Bachelors in Computer Science

100 Ryckman Ave Albany, NY, 12208 keenentopple@gmail.com 5184871443

Recent graduate of The University at Albany. Graduated with a degree in Computer Science and a 3.25 GPA. Experience in programming, software engineering, data analysis, data visualization, unit testing, front-end and back-end development, algorithims, and math. I work well in teams and I am familiar with most software development processes. Eager and active personality with strengths in customer service and listening.

Professional Experience

TVWS Data Analysis Researcher Thurman TVWS NetworkJanuary 2022 - May 2022

Working in a team of 3 along with UAlbany professor Dr. Zheleva, we captured, filtered, processed, and visualized an enormous amount of Television White Space Network packet data. Our team created a tool with the ability to withdraw specific data from these files and filter them into CSV files. We were then able to calculate specific data points from this data and graph them for research purposes such as network performance and stability. With this data analysis, we were able to provide the Admins of the TWWS network with data and suggestions on how to improve their network. Video explanation and source code are both available on my github.

Team Member Cyber Defense Organization ClubSeptember 2019 - May 2022

The CDO club was one of the most fun experiences I have had in my field. The club consisted of Red and Blue teams. Red teams attacked Networks and Blue teams defended them. Our club organized, and participated in many tournaments, some lasting 12 hours. My main objective was with the blue team; I organized and help complete tasks assigned to us by "CEO's" that would give us points towards a win. I got the chance to setup servers and learn a lot about how Operating Systems run. This club gave me experience in Cyber Security and Digital Forensics, as well as a good fear on how vulnerable we really are.

Server Innovo KitchenMay 2021 - Present

My entire work history has been with restaurants. I have experience in every position. My best strengths in this industry are customer service and listening with attention to detail.

Education

Computer Science in Software Engineering and Math University at Albany at Albany, NY August 2019 - May 2022

 $Focused\ study's\ in\ Software\ Development,\ Quality\ Assurance\ Testing,\ Algorithms\ and\ Formal\ Languages,\ as\ well\ as\ Math.$

Key Skills

- Programming Languages: C, Java, Python.
- Other Languages: SQL, HTML, JavaScript, AWK.
- Linux and Windows experience
- GitHub
- Proficient in Data Analysis and Data Visualization
- Math
- Listening and Attention to detail
- Wireshark/Tshark

Certifications

FEMA: Religious and Cultural Literacy and Competency in Disaster. | April 2020

FEMA: National Incident Management Sys. | April 2020

FEMA: Fundamentals of Emergency Management | May 2020

FEMA: Mitigation Planning for Local and Tribal Communities. | May 2020

FEMA: Introduction to Incident Command System, ICS-100. | March 2020

FEMA: Introduction to Homeland Security Planning. | March 2020

SoloLearn Java Mastery Certificate | August 2018

SoloLearn C Mastery Certificate | January 2019

SoloLearn Python Mastery Certificate | March 2020

Volunteer

Volunteer Firefighter in Coeymans from 2015-2020. Will take up again once I live in a neighborhood eligible to volunteer in.